Guide to the Fine Art Prints of New York City 1870-2003 (Bulk 1900-1940) PR 229
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
Fine Art Prints of New York City
1870-2003 (Bulk 1900-1940)
PR 229
© 2011 New-York Historical Society
4.02 Linear feet (3 boxes)
Collection of art prints showing views of and scenes in New York City. Includes engravings, etchings, lithographs, and other printmaking processes.
Provenance
Acquisition dates span the period of the collection. Specific dates of acquisition can often be found on the verso of each print.
Access Restrictions
Open to qualified researchers.
Photocopying undertaken by staff only. Limited to twenty exposures of stable, unbound material per day. See guidelines in Print Room for details.
Scope and Content Note
The Fine Art Prints of New York City collection spans the nineteenth and twentieth centuries. It is divided into three series by size: Medium Format Prints, Large Format Prints, and Oversize Prints.
Prints in the collection are mainly focused on the architecture and public life of New York City; points of local interest-including various skylines of Manhattan, the Brooklyn Bridge, Central Park, the New York Stock Exchange, the Woolworth Building, and the World Trade Center-are well-represented. Numerous prints depict religious architecture, including several views of Grace Church of Wall Street, and buildings of historical importance. Views of "old New York" are also common, including homesteads in Brooklyn and small historic views of homesteads and small homes in Manhattan. Only a few prints depict life in Chinatown or the poorer areas of the city. The prints from the first half of the twentieth century, however, are comprehensive in their portrayal of the increasingly modern New York -- images of skyscrapers, bridges, and commercial buildings abound.
The collection is mainly composed of etchings; a small percentage is engravings, lithographs, aquatints, or linoleum cuts. Notations on the format of the prints, and the edition number if known, can be found after the print title.
Important New York artists from throughout the twentieth century are represented in the collection. Artists with four or more prints include: Paul Berdanier, Arthur Cohen, K. Dehman, John Mackie Falconer, Agnes B. Fernbach, Albert Flanagan, Julius F. Gayler, Joseph W. Golinkin, Edward S. Hewitt, F. Leo Hunter, Nat Lowell, William Meyerowitz, Charles F.W. Mielatz, Betty Waldo Parish, Philip Reisman, Shunji Sakuyama, Anton Schutz, T.F. Simon, Emily Trueblood, William H. Wallace, Charles Henry White, Lawrence Nelson Wilbur, and Louis Wolchonok.
In addition, the collection includes small samples of the work of John Taylor Arms, Gottlob Briem, Fritz Eichenberg, Red Grooms, Richard Haas, Childe Hassam, Martin Lewis, James Pennell, Ernest D. Roth, and Richard Sloat.
Women printmakers found here include Isabel Bishop, Edith Bry, Mabel Dwight, Su-Li Hung, Yvonne Jacquette, Wuanita Smith, Caroline Phelps Stokes, and Karen Whitman, in addition to Fernbach, Parish, and Trueblood.
WPA printmakers found here include Lou Barlow, Sarah Berman, Hugh Botts, David Burke, and Ann Nooney.
Arrangement
The collection is divided into three series by size. Within each series, prints are arranged alphabetically by artist.
Series I. Medium Format Prints
Series II. Large Format Prints
Series III. Oversize Prints
Related Material at the Department of Prints, Photographs, and Architectural Collections
Similar works by many of the artists found within this collection can also be found in the James Boyd Collection of New York City Etchings (PR 007) and in the Printmaker File (PR 058).
Arms, John Taylor, 1887-1953; Berdanier, Paul F. (Paul Frederick), b. 1879.; Briem, Gottlob L; Cohen, Arthur (Arthur Morris), 1928-; Dehmann, Karl; Eichenberg, Fritz, 1901-1990; Falconer, John Mackie, 1820-1903; Fernbach, Agnes; Flanagan, Albert E.; Flanagan, Albert; Flatiron Building (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Gayler, Julius F.; Golinkin, Joseph W. $q (Joseph Webster), $d 1896-; Grooms, Red; Haas, Richard, 1936-; Hassam, Childe, 1859-1935; Hewitt, Edward Shepard, b. 1877; Hunter, F. Leo; Lowell, Nat; Meyerowitz, William, 1887-1981; Mielatz, Charles Frederick William, 1860-; New York Stock Exchange -- Pictorial works; Parish, Betty Waldo; Reisman, Philip, 1904-; Roth, Ernest David, 1879-1964; Schutz, Anton Joseph Freidrich, 1894-1977; Sloat, Richard, 1945-; Trueblood, Emily; Wallace, William Henry, 1838-1929; White, Charles Henry, b. 1878; Wolchonok, Lou; Woolworth Building (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Aquatints; Brooklyn Bridge (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Central Park (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Chromolithographs; Drypoints; Etchings; Greenwich Village (New York, N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Linocuts; Lithographs; New York (N.Y.) -- Buildings, structures, etc. -- Pictorial works; New York (N.Y.) -- Pictorial works; Prints; Skyscrapers -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works; Subways -- New York (State) -- New York -- Pictorial works; Woodcuts
- Series I: Medium Format Prints
  Scope and Contents note
  Series I contains prints size 16 x 20 inches and smaller. Prints are arranged alphabetically by artist's surname and title of print; titles listed are assigned by artist while [descriptions appear in brackets]. All prints are black and white etchings unless otherwise described; dates are given if inscribed by artist or in plate.
  - AIKMAN, Walter M. (1857-1939?
    - [W. & J. Sloane storefront, 245 Broadway at Murray [1843-1856], 1919 (Box 1)
  - ANDERSON, Clarence William (1891-1971)
    - The Last Stand [horse and carriage at Central Park], undated (Box 1)
  - ARMS, John Taylor (1887-1953)
    - Sketch, Grolier Club Library, Demonstration Print [2 copies], 1941 (Box 1)
  - BACHER, Otto (1856-1909)
    - [Central Park; model boats on lake], 1888 (Box 1)
  - BARLOW, Lou (1908- )
    - Sweet Potato Man, 1936 (Box 1)
      General note
      wood engraving
  - BEAL, Reynolds (1866-1951)
    - Brooklyn Bridge, 1929 (Box 1)
  - BERDANIER, Paul F., Sr. (1879-1947)
    - [Christopher Street, looking west] (5/7), undated (Box 1)
    - East River Nocturne, undated (Box 1)
    - Lower East Side- New York, undated (Box 1)
    - New York East Side, undated (Box 1)
  - BERMAN, Sarah (1895-1957)
    - Harlem Street Scene, ca. 1936-1942 (Box 1)
      General Note
      lithograph, published by Federal Art Project NYC WPA
  - BISHOP, Isabel (1902-1988)
    - [Three men on Fourteenth Street], 1986 (Box 1)
  - BOTTS, Hugh (1903-1964)
    - East River (Box 1)
      etching, published by Federal Art Project NYC WPA
  - BRIEM, Gottlob L. (1899-1972)
    - The Chrysler Building, New York City, N.Y., undated
      See: Series II
    - 6th Avenue N.Y.C., N.Y., undated (Box 1)
    - Power, Washington Bridge, undated (Box 1)
  - BROWNE, Syd J. (1907-91)
    - Riverside Viaduct, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Sutton Place, East River (imp. 4), 1938 (Box 1)
    - Sutton Place, N.Y., 1938 (Box 1)
  - BRUSSEL-SMITH, Bernard (1914-1989)
    - No. 8 Bowery (23/50), 1947 (Box 1)
  - BRY, Edith (1898-1992)
    - Cabbies, [1935] (Box 1)
      lithograph
    - Lunch at the Zoo (1/25), [1935] (Box 1)
  - BURKE, David (Box 1)
    - Going to Work, 1935 (Box 1)
      color screenprint, published by New York City WPA Art Project
  - CHAMBERLAIN, Samuel (1895-1975)
    - Manhattan Twilight (61/100), undated (Box 1)
      engraving
  - DEHMANN, Karl (1886-1974)
    - Giants & Dwarfs, [1915-20] (Box 1)
      drypoint etching
    - Grand Central Terminal, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Lower Broadway, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Liberty Glances at Manhattan, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Netherland, Savoy, Plaza, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Penn. R.R. Stn, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Pershing Square, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - St. Paul's Church, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Stock Exchange, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Temples Old & New, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - Towers of Gold, [1915-20] (Box 1)
    - The Way Called Broad, [1915-20] (Box 1)
  - DEVILLE, Henri (French 1871-?; active in US 1902-14)
    - City Hall Park (3/25), 1911 (Box 1)
  - DE WITT, Gerard
    - [Grand Central Station], undated (Box 1)
    - Pennsylvania Station], undated (Box 1)
  - DI CERBO, Michael (b.1947)
    - Parapets (19/70), 2001 (Box 1)
      etching and aquatint
  - DOLICE, Leon Louie (1892-1960)
    - Chrysler Building, undated (Box 1)
    - The East River N.Y., undated (Box 1)
    - The Little Church Around the Corner, undated (Box 1)
  - DWIGHT, Mabel (1876-1955)
    - Old Greenwich Village, 1928 (Box 1)
      lithograph, printed by George Miller
  - EICHENBERG, Fritz (1901-1990)
    - Subway, 1934 (Box 1)
      woodcut
  - FABRI, Ralph. (1894-1975)
    - A Day in the Park (6/50), [1945] (Box 1)
      etching with drypoint
  - FALCONER, John Mackie (1820-1903)
    - The Earliest Art Centre in New York City, No. 180 Fulton St., AD 1816, et. seq." [The Parker Clover], 1880 (Box 1)
      2 copie
    - First Methodist [Sanctuary] in New York City, 1880 (Box 1)
    - [House Where Robert Fulton Served his Apprenticeship], 1893 (Box 1)
    - 53 Maiden Lane [in]1842, Where Salmagundi was Published 1819" [J. Bucklass Tailor Shopfront], 1880 (Box 1)
      2 copies
    - [North Dutch Church, Corner of William and Fulton], 1882 (Box 1)
  - FERNBACH, Agnes B. (b. 1876)
    - A Bit of the Harlem River, 1922 (Box 1)
      printed by Ernest Roth
    - [Across Central Park Lake], 1929 (Box 1)
    - Across Central Park Lake, 1929 (Box 1)
    - [Boat houses along Hudson River], 1920 (Box 1)
    - [City Tree], 1932 (Box 1)
    - Cove, Central Park, undated (Box 1)
    - Gregorian Door, Jumel Mansion, 1921 (Box 1)
    - Organ & Choir, Old Temple Emanu-El, N.Y., undated (Box 1)
    - [Soldiers' and Sailors' Monument], undated (Box 1)
    - [Tree at Riverside], undated (Box 1)
    - [Synagogue interior], undated (Box 1)
  - FERRER, Henry
    - The Old Beach House: Corner of Cedar and Greenwich St, 1874 (Box 1)
    - On New York Bay, 1877 (Box 1)
  - FIENE, Ernest (1894-1965)
    - ['L' Train, baths, and barber shop](41/50), 1932 (Box 1)
  - FLANAGAN, Albert (1886-1969)
    - Afternoon Light, N.Y.C., 1930 (Box 1)
    - The Church Missions House, New York: the World Headquarters of the Episcopal Church, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y., 1931 (Box 1)
    - Dusk - William St., 1931 (Box 1)
    - The Fountain. Central Park - N.Y., 1933 (Box 1)
    - Harbor Sunset, N.Y., 1934 (Box 1)
    - Jacob Street, N.Y., 1931 (Box 1)
    - Manhattan - The City of Towers, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Manhattan Shore - East River N.Y., 1930 (Box 1)
    - 1931 (Box 1)
    - Morning Light, N.Y., 1934 (Box 1)
    - Night- New York, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Skyline-N.Y., 1933 (Box 1)
    - Storm at Sunset, 1932 (Box 1)
    - Towers of Manhattan - 42nd Street Group, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Towers of Manhattan - 57th Street Group, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Plaza Group - Towers of Manhattan, 1930 (Box 1)
    - Wall Street Group - Towers of Manhattan, 1931 (Box 1)
    - Waterfront, New York, 1933 (Box 1)
  - FLOTTEN, Cy
    - Brooklyn Bridge, 1935 (Box 1)
  - GAYLER, Julius F. (1872-1948)
    - The Eternal Light New York, 1935 (Box 1)
      aquatint
    - First Jewish Cemetery, 1934 (Box 1)
    - Grace Church, 1938 (Box 1)
    - MacDougal Alley, 1936 (Box 1)
    - Municipal Center, 1937 (Box 1)
    - New York Doorway [15 E. 81st], undated (Box 1)
    - New York Water Front [beginning of steel work for Empire State Building], 1930 (Box 1)
    - New York Water Front, 1938 (Box 1)
    - New York Water Front, 1939 (Box 1)
    - Saint Paul's Church, New York (proof), 1938 (Box 1)
    - Saint Paul's Church, New York (final take), 1938 (Box 1)
    - Washington Square South, 1936 (Box 1)
  - GREGORY, Frank M. (1848-?)
    - [Grace Church], undated (Box 1)
    - Twenty-Third St., Fifth Ave & Broadway, 1887 (Box 1)
      etching on silk
  - HALL, Charles B.
    - Block House and Gate, Foot of Wall St., undated (Box 2)
    - Old House, corner Broad and Exchange Place, undated (Box 2)
  - HANLEY, Frank
    - Jefferson Market Clock, undated (Box 2)
      block print
  - HASSAM, Childe (1859-1935)
    - [New York Stock Exchange Floor], 1927 (Box 2)
  - HEWITT, Edward S. (1877-1962)
    - Coal and Barges, undated (Box 2)
    - [East River Skyline], undated (Box 2)
    - [Midtown Towers, Waldorf Astoria], 1877 (Box 2)
    - Tugs and Towers, undated (Box 2)
  - HOOVER, Ellison (1888-1955)
    - [Washington Square Arch in winter], [1920-1930] (Box 2)
  - HOPPE, F. Werner (active ca. 1920-1930)
    - [Washington Square Arch], undated (Box 2)
      etching
  - HUNT, Leigh (1858-1959)
    - Hell Gate Bridge, 1917 (Box 2)
    - Washington Bridge, 1896 (Box 2)
  - HUNTER, F[rederick] Leo (1862-1943
    - Coenties Slip, South Street, 1881 (Box 2)
    - [Equitable Building], unadted (Box 2)
    - [Grace Church], 1903 (Box 2)
    - N.Y. Produce Exchange, 1887 (Box 2)
    - The Old New York University Building, 1878 (Box 2)
  - JACOBI, Eli (1898-1984)
    - At Sharkey's, 1939 (Box 2)
      linocut
  - JONES, Eugene Arthur (b. 1881)
    - [Express Office, Fulton Market], undated (Box 2)
    - [Pier 18- Fulton Market], undated (Box 2)
  - KANGMAN, Edwin
    - Brooklyn Bridge, undated (Box 2)
  - KING, L.H.
    - The Little Church Around the Corner, 1897 (Box 2)
  - KOSLOW, HOWARD (b. 1924)
    - The Bridge (36/100), 1983 (Box 2)
  - LANDECK, Armin (1905-1984)
    - Manhattan Nocturne, 1938 (Box 2)
      drypoint
  - LEVINE, Martin (b. 1945)
    - 42nd & 5th, 1998 (Box 2)
  - LEWIS, Martin (1882-1962)
    - Chance Meeting, 1940 (Box 2)
  - LOWELL, Nat (1880-1956)
    - [Brooklyn Bridge and lower Manhattan from Brooklyn], 1931 (Box 2)
    - Home of New York Chemical Mfg Co. 1824 [Tenth Ave.], undated (Box 2)
    - UN Headquarters, undated (Box 2)
    - [Washington Bridge, New York], 1931 (Box 2)
  - LUBBERS, Adriann (1892-1954)
    - Brooklyn Bridge (55/68), 1929 (Box 2)
  - MEISSNER, Leo (1895-1977)
    - Bleecker Street Follies (22/30), 1927 (Box 2)
      linoleum cut
    - Journal Square, Jersey City (9/30), 1925 (Box 2)
  - MEYEROWITZ, William (1887-1981)
    - Grant's Tomb, 1919 (Box 2)
    - Modern New York, 1933 (Box 2)
    - New York No. 1, or, 59th St. Bridge, 1931 (Box 2)
    - On the Hudson, 1918 (Box 2)
    - Passing the Arch of Victory, 1919 (Box 2)
  - MIELATZ, Charles Frederick William (1864-1919)
    - A Bit of Baxter Street, undated (Box 2)
    - [Aaron Burr's House, 11 Reade Street], 1898 (Box 2)
    - [Astor House], 1910 (Box 2)
    - Catherine Market with Brooklyn Bridge, 1903 (Box 2)
    - Cherry Street, 1904 (Box 2)
    - Coenties Slip, 1907 (Box 2)
    - Colonnade Lafayette St. de Milhaus Home, 1907 (Box 2)
    - The Dewey Arch, 1900 (Box 2)
    - [Dutch Reformed Church], 1898 (Box 2)
    - Elevated Station at Night, undated (Box 2)
    - Entrance to Brooklyn Bridge, 1892 (Box 2)
    - In the Bowery, undated (Box 2)
    - Jumel Mansion in Winter, 1911 (Box 2)
    - Lych Gate: Little Church around the Corner, [1902-1906] (Box 2)
    - No. 7 State Street, 1908 (Box 2)
    - Old Door on Houston Street, 1903 (Box 2)
    - Old Tom's on Thames Street, [1902-1906] (Box 2)
    - Oyster Market, Foot of Christopher St., 1903 (Box 2)
    - Rainy Day Broadway, 1892 (Box 2)
    - Rainy Night, Madison Square, 1890 (Box 2)
    - Restaurant in Mott Street, 1906 (Box 2)
    - Seaman's Church Institute on State Street, 1909 (Box 2)
    - [Wall Street, looking west to Trinity Church], undated (Box 2)
    - Washington Square, 1908 (Box 2)
    - [Windmill], 1887 (Box 2)
  - MOHN, Siguard M. (1891-
    - [St. Paul's Chapel, Broadway, N.Y.] (3/50), undated (Box 2)
  - MURPHY, Bill (b. 1952)
    - From Silver Lake (34/50), 1999 (Box 2)
  - NOONEY, Ann (1900-1964)
    - Fulton Street, Brooklyn, ca. 1935 (Box 2, Box 5)
  - PANTELL, Richard (1927- )
    - The Five Points, 1985 (Box 2)
    - Valentine Avenue, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Wishing Well, artist's proof, 1980 (Box 2)
  - PARISH, Betty Waldo (1908-1996)
    - Bleecker Street, 1938 (Box 2)
    - Doyer Street(3/10), 1936 (Box 2)
      etching and engraving
    - East of Gramercy (3/19), 1951 (Box 2)
    - Encroachment of a City (8/25), 1952 (Box 2)
      copper engraving
    - 14th Street & 5th Avenue, 1936 (Box 2)
    - Gay Street (12/22), 1937 (Box 2)
    - Grove and Bedford, 1937 (Box 2)
    - Marketing on Avenue A, 1936 (Box 2)
    - The Park from the Plaza (6/23), 1946 (Box 2)
      etching, engraving, and aquatint
    - Remembrance of Things Past (4/25), 1953 (Box 2)
    - Third Avenue and 11th Street (13/20), 1936 (Box 2)
    - Thompson Street, 1938 (Box 2)
    - 2 West 15th St., 1950 (Box 2)
    - Washington Square South (11/31), 1939 (Box 2)
  - PATTERSON, Charles Robert (1878-1958)
    - Ship "Bangalore" at South St., 1898, 1948 (Box 2)
  - PELLETIERI, Michael (b. 1947)
    - City Signs, 2003 (Box 2)
  - PENNELL, Joseph (1866-1922)
    - Fifth Avenue Building, undated (Box 1)
  - PERARD, Victor (1867-1957
    - Looking Up Broadway New York From No. 1 B'way, 1909 (Box 2)
    - The Old Hansom Cab, 1904 (Box 2)
      soft ground etching
  - PETRULIS, Alan (b. 1954)
    - City of Ships (30/100), undated (Box 2)
    - White Street (30/100), 1977 (Box 2)
  - PLATT, C.A. (1861-1933)
    - Shanties on the Harlem, [1880] (Box 2)
  - PLATT, Peter, J.
    - King Bridge, N.Y., 1917 (Box 2)
      after a painting by C. A. Platt, 1884
    - Old Lorillard Snuff Mill, Bronx River, 1912 (Box 2)
  - PLOWMAN, George T. (1869-1932)
    - Capt. Adrian Van Brunt Homestead, Brooklyn N.Y. (3/50), undated (Box 2)
    - Capt. Jan Schenck Homestead, Brooklyn N.Y. (3/50), undated (Box 2)
    - Lefferts Homestead (3/50), undated (Box 2)
    - Wyckoff Homestead, Brooklyn, N.Y. (3/50), undated (Box 2)
  - PRICE, CHESTER B. (1885-1962)
    - Manhattan Forum, undated (Box 2)
  - QUINLAN, Will J. (1877-1919)
    - Fulton Street, 1923 (Box 3)
  - REID, Andrew
    - Grand Central, undated (Box 3)
  - REISMAN, PHILIP (1904-1992)
    - Builders I (60/100), 1928 (Box 3)
    - Builders II (99/100), 1928 (Box 3)
    - Fruit Wagon (23/100), 1929 (Box 3)
    - The Knife Grinder (38/100), 1929 (Box 3)
    - The Meeting (27/100), 1930 (Box 3)
    - Moving Day (26/100), 1929 (Box 3)
    - Neighborhood Park (33/100), 1929 (Box 3)
    - Peddler (34/100), 1928 (Box 3)
    - Peddlers Under the 'L' (37/100), 1928 (Box 3)
    - Pershing Square (75/100), undated (Box 3)
    - Soda Fountain (42/100), 1928 (Box 3)
    - Veterans - World War I (40/100), 1931 (Box 3)
  - ROTH, Ernest D. (1879-1964)
    - Coenties Slip, N.Y., 1935 (Box 3)
  - RUZICKA, Rudolph (1883-1978)
    - [St. John's Chapel, 40 Varick St.] (33/75), 1911 (Box 3)
    - [Clapboard house overlooking river], [1909] (Box 3)
  - SABIN, Joseph F. (1846-1926)
    - [New York Produce Exchange from Castle Garden], ca. 1895 (Box 3)
  - SCHMIDT, Louis
    - Mountains [Hanover Square], 1929 (Box 3)
  - SCHUMANN, Karl
    - Temples Old and New, undated (Box 3)
  - SCHUTZ, Anton (1894-1977)
    - [East River Bridges], undated (Box 3)
    - 544 Hotel Waldorf Astoria, undated (Box 3)
    - George Washington Bridge (96/100), undated (Box 3)
    - Madison Square, undated (Box 3)
  - SHARP, William (1900-1961)
    - Spanish Quarter, New York (5/50), undated (Box 3)
    - Third Avenue Nocturne, undated (Box 3)
  - SHAW, Robert (1859-1912
    - Fraunces Tavern, New York, printed for members of the Colonial Society of America, [1906] (Box 3)
  - SMITH, Wuanita (1866-1959)
    - Columbus Jewels, undated (Box 3)
  - STOKES, Caroline Phelps (1854-1909)
    - [Residence of Anson Greene Phelps, East River and 30th], undated (Box 3)
  - STURGES, Dwight Case (1874-1940)
    - #1 Broadway, after 1921 (Box 3)
  - TITTLE, Walter Ernest (1883-1966)
    - Manhattan Minarets, undated (Box 3)
  - TROWBRIDGE, Vaughan (1869-1945)
    - [London Terrace], undated (Box 3)
      color etching
  - TRUEBLOOD, Emily (b. 1942)
    - City Towers (2/50), 1994 (Box 3)
    - Night Tower(31/50), 2000 (Box 3)
    - Rooftop View 1 (16/50), 2000 (Box 3)
    - World Trade View (31/50), 1995 (Box 3)
  - VANDERHOOK, ?
    - St. John the Divine, undated (Box 3)
  - VAN NOTTI, Henry (1878-1962)
    - Barclay St., New York, [1915] (Box 3)
    - New and Old New York, [1910] (Box 3)
  - WALCOT, William (1874-1943)
    - Brooklyn Bridge, [1920] (Box 3)
  - WALKER, Steven (b. 1955)
    - Sunset Skyline, 1999 (Box 3)
  - WALL, Bernhardt (1872-1956)
    - Italian Church on Minetta Lane, 1918 (Box 3)
    - Ten Etchings of Greenwich Village Landmarks in the War Year of 1918, 1947 (Box 3)
      bound booklet
  - WALLACE, William H.
    - Ann Street, corner Theatre Alley, undated (Box 3)
    - Bradburns Bookstall, undated (Box 3)
    - The Burdell House at 31 Bond Street, undated (Box 3)
    - Fog Under Bridge Tower, 1882 (Box 3)
    - Fulton Street [(Brooklyn) Between Johnson and Myrtle Ave East Side], 1845 (Box 3)
    - [Grape Vine Inn; Last of the Shades], undated (Box 3)
    - Harlem River in 1870 (Box 3)
      2 copies, different sizes
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (proof), 1882 (Box 3)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (final), 1882 (Box 3)
    - Middle Dutch Reform Church (2nd state), 1882 (Box 3)
    - [New York from Staten Island (?)], 1890 (Box 3)
    - Old New York, undated (Box 3)
    - [Post Office at Cedar and Nassau Streets], 1888 (Box 3)
    - [Prospect Park - Apple Trees], undated (Box 3)
  - WALLER, Frank (1842-1923)
    - [Museum interior], 1893 (Box 3)
  - WARD, Lynd (1905-1985)
    - Under the El, undated (Box 3)
  - WERGER, Art (b.1955)
    - Attraction, 2003 (Box 3)
      mezzotint
    - Daybreak (56/75), 1997 (Box 3)
    - Early Thaw (72/75), 1996 (Box 3)
  - WHITE, Charles Henry (1878-1918)
    - Bit of Bleecker St. (3/10), 1903 (Box 3)
    - Bleecker St. Gables, N.Y., 1903 (Box 3)
    - Boiler Works [David M. Nichols Boiler Works], 1902 (Box 3)
    - East River Bridge II, 1903 (Box 3)
    - Five Points, N.Y., undated (Box 3)
    - Hudson Street (16/25), undated (Box 3)
    - Mulberry Bend, N.Y., 1903 (Box 3)
    - Old Warf II, Third State, undated (Box 3)
    - [Shipsmith and blacksmith shop], undated (Box 3)
    - The Tenement, Third State, 1903 (Box 3)
    - Thompson Street Inn, Fifth State, undated (Box 3)
  - WILBUR, Lawrence Nelson (1897-1988)
    - Along the Docks (5/50), [1945] (Box 3)
      after his watercolor
    - The East River, 1946 (Box 3)
    - Manhattan Mountains, 1938 (Box 3)
    - Old Brownstones - New York (16/50), 1923 (Box 3)
    - Peck's Slip - N.Y.C. (proof), 1938 (Box 3)
    - September- Central Park (32/50), undated (Box 3)
    - The Spire [Empire State Building] (4/100), undated (Box 3)
    - Under the Bridge (6/27), 1988 (Box 3)
    - [Produce stands] (7/75), 1976 (Box 3)
    - [Produce stands] (9/75), 1976 (Box 3)
  - WOLCHONOK, Louis (1898 - 1973)
    - Bridge, Sheepshead Bay (71/150), undated (Box 3)
    - Fort Lee Ferry (28/150), undated (Box 3)
    - Fourteenth Street, undated (Box 3)
    - Hellgate Bridge (1/150), undated (Box 3)
    - [New York Telephone and Telegraph Building] (25/150), undated (Box 3)
    - [Saint Paul's], undated (Box 3)
    - [Sheepshead Bay] (40/150), undated (Box 3)
    - [Spring in Central Park], undated (Box 3)
    - [Street Construction, New York] (7/150), undated (Box 3)
    - Subway Construction at 8th Ave. and 116th St., 1926 (Box 3)
    - [Riverside Park with bridge] (1st proof, 2nd state), undated (Box 3)
    - [Weber Coal Company], undated (Box 3)
      [Attributed]
    - [Woolworth Building], undated (Box 3)
- Series II: Large Format Prints
  Series II contains prints larger than 16 x 20 inches and smaller than 30 x 40 inches. Prints are arranged alphabetically by artist's surname and title of print; titles listed are assigned by artist while [descriptions appear in brackets]. All prints are black and white etchings unless otherwise described; dates are given if inscribed by artist or in plate.
  - BEAMLEY, William Jean